Friedlander, Walter A.; Papers ger003
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. Friedländer, 1931-1984; 3; 341 folders
  - Manuscripts of journal articles, 3.2
    - Book reviews (German and English), Undated; 3.2.3
      - Weiland, Ruth.Das soziale Schicksal der deutschen landwirtschaftlichen Wanderfamilien, 1932 (Box 34 (3.2.3-Book reviews (German and English)), Folder 337)
      - Weiland, Ruth.Die Kinder der Arbeitslosen, 1933 (Box 34 (3.2.3-Book reviews (German and English)), Folder 338)
      - Weiland, Ruth.Kinderfürsorge jenseits unserer Grenzen, undated (Box 34 (3.2.3-Book reviews (German and English)), Folder 339)
      - Weyl, Richard.Der Jugendliche im Recht, 1932 (Box 34 (3.2.3-Book reviews (German and English)), Folder 340)
      - Wilson, Thelma / Eileen Younghusband.Teaching Community Work: A European Exploration, 1976 (Box 34 (3.2.3-Book reviews (German and English)), Folder 341)
      - Hueser, Karl / Ferdinand Kuepper / Wilhelm Beckers.Politische Bildung in Deutschland im 20. Jahrhundert, 1976 (Box 34 (3.2.3-Book reviews (German and English)), Folder 341)
      - Schneider, Alfred.Rechts- und Berufskunde fuer Medizinische Assistenzberufe, 1976 (Box 34 (3.2.3-Book reviews (German and English)), Folder 341)
- Publications by Walter A. Friedländer, 1926-1979; 4; 155 folders
  The first section (18 folders) contains book-length publications and/or reviews of those publications. The second section contains offprints or clippings of journal and newspaper articles, in German and in English (138 folders) and dating from 1926-1979. Many articles date from the 1930s, are written in German, and deal with youth welfare topics.
  - Book publications (including reviews), 4.1
    - Grundzüge des Jugendrechts. Leipzig: Ernst Oldenburg, 1924; 98p. (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 1)
    - Jugendrecht und Jugendpflege. Berlin: Arbeiterjugend-Verlag, 1930; 116p (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 2)
    - Das Recht der Jugend -- reviews, 1930 (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 3)
    - The Swiss Federal Criminal Code of December 21, 1937, 1939 May-1939 June; 86p. (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 4)
      Published as a supplement to The Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, XXX, No. 1.
    - The Swiss Federal Criminal Code of December 21, 1937 -- reviews, Undated (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 5)
    - Child Welfare in Germany Before and After Naziism -- reviews, 1940 (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 6)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare. New York: Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1955; 683p. (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 7)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- reviews, 1955 (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 8)
    - Concepts and Methods of Social Work -- reviews, advertisements, 1958 (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 9)
    - Helene Simon. Ein Leben für soziale Gerechtigkeit -- reviews, 1962 (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 10)
    - Individualism & Social Welfare. An Analysis of the System of Social Security and Social Welfare in France. East Lansing, MI: The Free Press of Glencoe, Inc., 1962; 251p. (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 11)
    - Individualism & Social Welfare -- reviews, 1962 (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 12)
    - Hans Maier. Sein Leben und Werk. Bonn: Arbeiterwohlfahrt, 1964; 39p. (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 13)
    - Grundbegriffe und Methoden der Sozialarbeit -- reviews, 1974 (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 14)
    - International Aspects of Social Work and Social Welfare -- reviews, 1975 (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 15)
    - Calkins, Kenneth R.Hugo Haase: Democrat and Revolutionary. Durham, NC: Carolina Academic Press, 1979 (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 16)
      Unbound copy.
    - Hugo Haase -- reviews, Undated (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 17)
  - Journal articles, 4.2
    - "Praktische Erfahrungen mit der Schutzaufsicht", (1926) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 18)
    - "Gesetzentwurf über die unehelichen Kinder", (1926) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 19)
    - "Die gesetzlliche Regelung der Unterbringung und Versorgung des Pflegekindes", (1926) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 20)
    - "Die Jugend in der Gesetzgebung", (1926) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 21)
    - "Die Rechtsgrundlage der Zuständigkeit in der freien Wohlfahrtspflege", (1926) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 22)
    - "Die erzieherischen Aufgaben des Jugendamtes", (1927) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 23)
    - "Jugendwohlfahrtspflege und Sozialpolitik. Vortragsdisposition", (1927) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 24)
    - "Der Leiter der Jugendgerichtshilfe", [ca. 1927] (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 25)
    - "Zur gesellschaftlichen Stellung der heutigen Familie. Erfahrungen aus der Jugendfürsorge", (1928) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 26)
    - "Reichskonferenz des Hauptausschusses für Arbeiterwohlfahrt", (1929) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 27)
    - "Die Schwiegepflicht der Mitglieder der Wohlfahrts- und Jugendkommission", (1929) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 28)
    - "Der Stand des Gesetzes über unehelichen Kinder", (1929) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 29)
    - "Abänderungsvorschläge zur Fürsorgeerziehung", (1930) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 30)
    - "Jugendamt und Säuglings- und Kleinkinderfürsorge", (1930) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 31)
    - "Die Bedeutung der Schutzaufsicht für die Fürsorgeerziehung", [1931] (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 32)
    - "Breulich, Franz, 'Das Wiener Jugendhilfswerk 1930'", (1931) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 33)
    - "Hilfe des Jugendamts", (1931) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 34)
    - "Kleinkindererholung und Familienfürsorge", (1931) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 35)
    - "Notprogramm der Jugendwohlfahrtspflege. Vorschläge der Deutschen Zentrale für freie Jugendwohlfahrt", (1931) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 36)
    - "Sparmaßnahmen in der Jugendwohlfahrtspflege", (1931) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 37)
    - "Wo stehen wir heute?", (1931) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 38)
    - "Arbeitslose Jugend", (1932) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 39)
    - "Eine neue Adoptionsvermittlungsstelle?", (1932) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 40)
    - "Lebensraum der Arbeitslosen Jugend!", (1932) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 41)
    - "Noch einmal: Die Deutsche Adoptionsstelle. Eine Erwiderung", (1932) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 42)
    - "Weyl, Richard, Prof. Dr. (Kiel): Der Jugendliche im Recht", (1932) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 43)
    - "Zusammenarbeit von Jugendamt und Polizeibehörden", (1932) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 44)
    - "Arbeitslosigkeit und Kinderarbeit", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 45)
    - "Deutsche Emigranten in Paris", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 46)
    - "Erfahrungen in der deutschen Fürsorge für jugendliche Arbeitslose", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 47)
    - "Die Frau im Recht", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 48)
    - "Das Jugendnotwerk in der Praxis", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 49)
    - "Los der Armen in Dritten Reich", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 50)
    - "Mietrückstände", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 51)
    - "Notwerk der arbeitslosen Jugend. Kritische Anmerkungen", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 52)
    - "Schwarzarbeit und Emigration", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 53)
    - "Soziale Probleme der deutschen Emigration (I)", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 54)
    - "Soziale Probleme der deutschen Emigration (II)", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 54)
    - "Waldhof Templin", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 55)
    - "Das Jugendwohlfahrtsrecht", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 55)
    - "Die Wandlung der deutschen Fürsorge", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 56)
    - "Zur Frage gesetzlicher Regelung der sozialen Gerichtshilfe", (1933) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 57)
    - "Sozialistische Stellung zur privaten Wohlfahrtspflege", (1934) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 58)
    - "Die heutige wohlfahrtspflegerische Mission der Schweiz", (1935) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 59)
    - "Die amerikanische Nationale Konferenz für Wohlfahrtspflege", (1937) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 60)
    - "Bekämpfung der Arbeitslosigkeit in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1937) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 61)
    - "Große Zunahme der Jugendkriminalität", (1937) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 62)
    - "Die neuen Methoden der amerikanischen Gewerkschaftsbewegung", (1937) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 63)
    - "Sexualverbrechen unter Hitler", (1937) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 64)
    - "Sozialarbeit in USA. Die 'National Conference of Social Work' in Indianapolis -- Eine riesige Beteiligung", (1937) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 65)
    - "Sozialpolitische Sorgen in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1937) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 66)
    - "Der Stand der amerikanischen Gewerkschaftsentwicklung", (1937) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 67)
    - "What Some 'Aryan' Germans Think of Hitler", (1937) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 68)
    - "Der amerikanische 'Social Security Act' in der Praxis", (1938) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 69)
    - "Die amerikanische Sozialpolitik im Aufbau: Der Social Security Act", (1938) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 70)
    - "Die deutsche Schipperkrankheit", (1938) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 71)
    - "Ein amerikanisches Jugendgerichtsgesetz", (1938) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 72)
    - "Kongress am falschen Ort. Internationaler Kinderschutzkongress in Deutschland", (1938) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 73)
    - "Kulturbild aus Nazi-Deutschland. 'Erziehung' mit der Hundepeische. -- Das Rechsgericht findet Kindermisshandlung entschuldbar", (1938) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 74)
    - "Zur gewerkschaftlichen Entwicklung der 'social workers' in den USA", (1938) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 75)
    - "Die amerikanische Wohlfahrtskonferenz in Seattle", (1939) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 76)
    - "The Buffalo Conference of Social Work 1939" (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 77)
    - "Social Security im Vormarsch", (1939) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 78)
    - "Die Völkerwanderung unserer Zeit", (1939) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 79)
    - "Wohin mit den Millionen Emigranten?", (1939) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 80)
    - "Social Work Under the Nazi Regime", (1939) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 81)
    - "Zum Gesundheitsfürsorge-Programm in U.S.A", (1939) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 82)
    - "Kinder in einer Demokratie. Die Jugendhilfe-Konferenz im Weissen Hause, Washington, D.C", (1940) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 83)
    - "Julius Rosenwald. The Life of a Practical Humanitarian. By M. R. Werner", (1940) (Box 35 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 84)
    - "Die beste Verteidigung der Freiheit", (1941) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 85)
    - "Pre-Nazi Prison", (1941) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 86)
    - "Zur Frage der Immigranten-Arbeit in Illinois", (1941) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 87)
    - "Jugendliche Kriminalität im Kriege. Erfahrungen in England und in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1942) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 88)
    - "Probleme der Gesundheitsfürsorge im Kriege in USA", (1942) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 89)
    - "Die Schweiz im Kriege", (1942) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 90)
    - "Landes-Wohlfahrtskongreß in New Orleans", (1943) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 91)
    - "Die Haltung amerikanischer Kinder zum Krieg", (1945) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 92)
    - "UNRRA, die internationale Nothilfe der neuen Weltorganisation", (1946) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 93)
    - "Die Welt-Gesundheits-Organisation", (1947) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 94)
    - "Die Aufgaben des Internationalen Kinder-Notfonds", (1948) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 95)
    - "Entwicklungstendenzen der sozialen Arbeit in den Vereinigten Staaten von Nordamerika nach dem zweiten Weltkrieg", (1948) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 96)
    - "International Aspects of Social Work Education", (1949) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 97)
    - "Gewerkschaftsverträge und soziale Sicherheit", (1950) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 98)
    - "Reform des amerikanischen Social Security Act", (1950) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 99)
    - "The Challenge of Delinquency. Von Negley K. Teeters und John Otto Reinemann", (1951) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 100)
    - "Das Stpendienwesen für Berufslehren in USA", (1951) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 101)
    - "Familienfürsorge in Frankreich", (1952) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 102)
    - "Berlin Refugees", (1953) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 103)
    - "Child Welfare", (1953) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 104)
    - "Co-ordination of Family Welfare Services in France", (1953) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 105)
    - "Freiwillige Krankenversicherung unter der Kaiser-Stiftung in Kalifornien", (1953) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 106)
    - "Das neue Bundesministerium für Gesundheit, Erziehung und Wohlfahrt in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1953) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 107)
    - "The New Refugees in Germany: A Challenge to Social Work", (1953) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 108)
    - "Der Ausbau der Sozialversicherung in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1954) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 109)
    - "Erfahrungen mit Ambulatorien in Amerika", (1954) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 110)
    - "Fürsorgerische Mitwirkung bei der Behandlung chronisch Geisteskranker. Ergebnisse eines Experiments in Kalifornien", (1954) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 111)
    - "Internationale Sozialkonferenz in Toronto", (1954) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 112)
    - "Zur Entwicklung der amerikanischen Sozialpolitik", (1954) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 113)
    - "Die amerikanische Wohlfahrtskonferenz in San Francisco 1955" (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 114)
    - "Das Berufsbildungswesen in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1955) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 115)
    - "Selbsthilfe in internationaler Beleuchtung", (1955) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 116)
    - "Die Stellung des unehelichen Kindes in Amerika", (1955) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 117)
    - "Aufgaben und Zusammenarbeit der privaten und staatlichen Jugendhilfe in den USA", (1957) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 118)
    - "Berufsschulwesen in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1957) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 119)
    - "Amerikanisches Wohlfahrtswesen und die Gewerkschaften", (1958) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 120)
    - "Zur Frage der Voraussagbarkeit des Bewährungserfolges", (1958) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 121)
    - "Harry C. Bredemeier und Jackson Toby, Social Problems in America", (1960) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 122)
    - "In memoriam Carl Mennicke" / "In memoriam Hans Scherpener", (1960) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 123)
    - "Sozialfürsorge und Sozialwissenschaft", (1960) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 124)
    - "White House Conference on Children in USA", (1960) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 125)
    - "Wandlung der Grundgedanken sozialer Arbeit mit besonderer Berücksichtigung der nordamerikanischen Verhältnisse", (1961) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 126)
    - "A Statement of Guiding Principles on Standards of the Compulsory Education and Child Labor Laws, by Gloria Bley", (1962) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 127)
    - "Elternhaus und Schule; ein Beitrag zur inneren Schulreform: Kurt Diederich", (1962) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 128)
    - "Gemeinschaftsplanung und Gemeinschaftsentwicklung in den USA", (1962) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 129)
    - "Helene Simons frühe Arbeiten über Sozialpolitik und Wohlfahrtspflege", (1962) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 130)
    - "Jugendarbeitschutz, by Dr. Paul Seipp, Dr. Walter Becker, and Dr. Gerhard Potrykus", (1962) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 131)
    - "Jugendliche Banden in Amerika, ihre soziologische Rolle und Maßnahmen der Fürsorge", (1962) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 132)
    - "Probleme der Jugendfürsorge in afrikanischen Entwicklungsländern", (1962) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 133)
    - "Vorbeugende und heilende Maßnahmen der Fürsorge für verwahrloste Jugendliche in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1962) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 134)
    - "Zur Berufslage der amerikanischen Sozialarbeiter", (1962) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 135)
    - "Lotte Lemke zum 60. Geburtstag unsere Wünsche und Grüße!", (1963) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 136)
    - "Nochmals: Jugendfürsorge in afrikanischen Entwicklungsländern", (1963) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 137)
    - "Zur Krise der öffentlichen Wohlfahrtspflege in USA", (1963) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 138)
    - "Clarke A. Chambers: Seedtime of Reform. American Social Service and Social Action, 1918-1933", (1964) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 139)
    - "Gefahren des Überflusses", (1964) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 140)
    - "In memoriam Hans Maier", (1964) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 141)
    - "Das amerikanische Krankenhaus-Versicherungsgesetz von 1965" (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 142)
    - "Gewerkschaftliche Organisation der Sozialarbeiter in den USA", (1965) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 143)
    - "Jugend im Konflikt mit der Gesellschaft", (1965) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 144)
    - "Re: Familie Kautsky", (1965) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 145)
    - "Recenti orientamenti della formazione per il servizio sociale negli Stati Uniti", (1965) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 146)
    - "Neue amerikanische Sozialgesetzgebung", (1966) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 147)
    - "Neue Methoden der Sozialausbildung in den USA", (1966) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 148)
    - "Siegmund-Schultze als Gründer und Erster Direktor des Jugendamtes Berlin und sein Einfluß auf das Reichsjugendwohlfahrtsgesetz", (1966) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 149)
    - "The Federal Correctional Rehabilitation Study Act of 1965 and Its Implications", (1967) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 150)
    - "Labour Unions and Social Workers", (1970) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 151)
    - "Briefe, die uns erreichen" [letter to the editor], (1975) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 152)
    - "The First Thirty Years (An autobiographical study), Fred G. Lennhoff", (1976) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 153)
    - "'Sühnezeichen' musste Blutopfer bringen", (1978) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 154)
    - "Letter to NASW", (1979) (Box 36 (4-Publications by Walter A. ), Folder 155)
- Conference Materials, 1936-1981; 5; 64 folders
  Among the conferences represented are ten of the International Conferences of Social Work/Welfare, 1936-1974, as well as the Conference on the Law of the Poor, held in Berkeley, CA, 17-19 February 1966 (18 folders; primarily texts of lectures).
  - International Conferences on Social Work / Social Welfare, (1936-1974); 5.1
    - Third International Conference on Social Work, London, England, 1936 July 08-1936 July 10 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 1)
    - Eighth International Conference of Social Work, Munich, Germany, 1956 August 05-1956 August 10 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 2)
    - Tenth International Conference of Social Work, Rome, Italy, 8-14 January 1961 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 3)
    - Eleventh International Conference of Social Work, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 9-25 August 1962 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 4)
    - Twelfth International Conference of Social Service, Athens, Greece, 13-19 September 1964 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 5)
    - Thirteenth International Conference of Social Work, Washington, D.C., 31 August-10 September 1966 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 6)
    - Fourteenth International Conference on Social Welfare, Helsinki, Finland, 18-24 August 1968 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 7)
    - Fifteenth International Congress of Schools of Social Work, Manilla, Philippine Islands, 30 August-2 September 1970 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 8)
    - Sixteenth International Conference on Social Welfare, The Hague, Netherlands, 1972 August (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 9)
    - Seventeenth International Conference on Social Welfare, Nairobi, Kenya, 14-20 July 1974 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Conference materials, (1926-1981); 5.2
    - Miscellaneous conference announcements, 1944-1981 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 11)
    - Sozialismus und Bevölkerungspolitik, Jena, Germany, 25-26 September 1926 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 12)
    - Congrès international de l"Enfance / Internationaler Kongress für die Kindheit, Paris, 27 July-1 August 1931 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 13)
    - Xe Session de l'Association internationale pour la protection de l'enfance, Lisbonne, 25-29 October 1931 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 14)
    - Konferenz zur Erhaltung der Jugendwohlfahrtspflege, Berlin, 7 December 1931 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 15)
    - German-American Institute, Frankfurt am Main, 1932 July 09-1932 July 10 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 16)
    - Der soziale Wandel und die Erziehung. Sechste Weltkonferenz des Weltbundes für Erneuerung dr Erziehung. Nizza, 29 July-12 August 1932 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 17)
    - Schweizerische Konferenz für sozialistische Wohlfahrtspflege, Luzern, 12 November 1933 (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 18)
    - American Association of Social Workers. Minutes of meetings, (1951-1953) (Box 37 (5-Conference Materials), Folder 19)